Rawle Becerril

Software Engineer

(240)-476-2349 · rbecerril@rbcoder.dev · Washington, D.C. · rbcoder.dev · github.com/rawlenightlong

About Me

As a pragmatic, full-stack software developer with a decade's worth of program management, cross-functional collaboration, and project delivery excellence, I am an invaluable asset to any high-functioning team.

Skills & Tech Stack

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, Typescript
Libraries & Frameworks - React, Node, Express.JS, Django, jQuery, Nextjs
Database - Postgres, SQL, MongoDB, NoSQL
Other - RESTful APIs, JSON, Tailwind, Web API, JWT, Git, Ajax, Bootstrap

Professional Experience

Freelance, Junior Front-End Developer

May 2023 - October 2023

- Executed front-end development work alongside Lead Developer for a NextJS / TypeScript / Prisma desktop application
- Refactored input select code to work with previously defined prop types & interfaces to reduce redundant code
- Designed React web components to dynamically display client lists from updated queries

SiriusXM, Music Programming Director

February 2020 - Current

- Leading the programming philosophy and scheduling operations of three music channels, including playlist curation, engaging copy-writing, and overall programming strategy to attract listeners of all demographics.
- Coordinating and directing cross-functional departments (PR, Programming, Digital, Production, Engineering, etc.) to deliver exclusive and entertaining on-air broadcasts for subscribers under tight deadlines.

SiriusXM, Assistant Music Programmer

February 2018 - February 2020

- Coordinated daily scheduling operations of leading dance channels, including *Electric Area, Diplo's Revolution, Insomniac Radio*, and *Studio 54 Radio* to ensure proper schedule airing.
- Demonstrated leadership by quarterbacking marathon broadcast sessions from around the world, including Miami's Ultra Music Festival and Belgium's Tomorrowland Music Festival.

Software Development Projects

September 2022 - Present

Rawlify | Full-Stack Web Application | NextJS, Tailwind, Javascript, CSS, Express, Mongo DB, Spotify API

- Next.js, Tailwind, and Express, and Node application allowing users to build playlists using a premium Spotify account
- Utilized NextJS's internal web API functionality to facilitate Spotify user account authentication
- Implemented Tailwind and vanilla CSS for a clean, responsive UI / UX on the go

RawleTube | Full Stack Web Application | ReactJS, Django, CSS, Postgres, YouTube API

- React front-end, Django back-end video tracking app allowing users to track YouTube links with a Django REST Framework API
- Displayed stored videos in a React component card with external links to the video and embedded players for easy playback
- Incorporated YouTube API calls to dynamically display video thumbnails and embed videos

CETAMD | Full-Stack Web App | HTML, CSS, React, Express, MongoDB, Google Maps API

- React.js, Express, Mongo DB, Node event-tracking app to allow users to track their scheduled events on a Google Map
- Setup initial Express REST route design and reviewed branch conflicts and merges / deployment of new code in Github
- Integration of Google's Places & Maps web API to display user's input event location on the CRUD Read route

Education

General Assembly | Remote Coding Bootcamp

Full Stack Software Engineering Immersive

September 2022 - April 2023

An intensive, 450+ hour program focused on front end and back end development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data structures and algorithms, teamwork, relational databases, technical problems & solutions, and best practices & strategy.

University of Maryland | College Park, Maryland

Bachelors of Arts in Criminal Justice & Criminology

August 2009 - January 2014